<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Ayyappa Deeksha</string>
    <string name="forgotten_account">Forgotten account?</string>
    <string name="new_user">New User</string>
    <string name="title_activity_play_music">PlayMusicActivity</string>
    <string name="title_activity_navigation_drawer">NavigationDrawerActivity</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="nav_header_title">9876543210</string>
    <string name="nav_header_subtitle">test@gmail.com</string>
    <string name="nav_header_desc">Navigation header</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="title_activity_registration">RegistrationActivity</string>
    <string name="change_password">Change Password</string>
    <string name="logout">Logout</string>
    <string name="btn_update">Update</string>

    <string name="btn_register_here">Register Here</string>
    <string name="btn_login">Login</string>
    <string name="btn_login_otp">Login with OTP</string>
    <string name="hint_or">OR</string>
    <string name="hint_mobile_number_or_email">Mobile number</string>

    <string name="hint_login_as_swamy">Login as Swamy</string>
    <string name="hint_login_as_vendor">Login as Vendor</string>


    <string name="hint_vendor_text">If you want to become a vendor, please register
        as vendor. </string>


    <string name="google_maps_key" templateMergeStrategy="preserve" translatable="false">
        AIzaSyAr1lZXmrMw-YcaTUL-fLqRT0tA6YStNrk
    </string>

    <!--<string name="google_maps_key" templateMergeStrategy="preserve" translatable="false">
        AIzaSyBsT8BN8fayccpJXya0VGx7DD64-JmtrLI
    </string>-->


    <!-- AIzaSyBsT8BN8fayccpJXya0VGx7DD64-JmtrLI
    	AIzaSyCxXsttdNsqwsOZRv0rNIpRvAF6yQexL1o-->


    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello Blank Fragment</string>
    <string name="importance_of_deeksha">In Bhagawat Gita, Lord Krishna declared: "The one who loves everyone, treats both pleasure and pain with equanimity,  is friendly to all beings, compassionate, ego-less, patient, always contended, self-controlled, determined, and who dedicates his mind and intellect to me is dear to me and is my true devotee.”

Ayyappa Vratham is a set of spiritual exercises to enable one to begin the journey towards becoming a true devotee. The ultimate purpose of Ayyappa Vratham is self-transformation. The process helps the Sadhaks -seekers of the Divine - to realize that we are part of the divinity. For the benefit of new devotees and the next generation of young devotees, in what follows, we describe the importance, significance, and the benefits of Ayyappa Vratham.

Why Observe Ayyappa Vratham?
Ayyappa Vratham is a good entry point to the spiritual world, particularly to those who are used to rituals as the basis for devotion. According to the Sanadhana Dharma, followed in India based on the Vedic traditions, man (jeevaatma) seeking the union with God (paramaatma) is the ultimate spiritual purpose of human life. However, there are several margas - pathways-to reach God-Raja Yoga, Bhakti Yoga, Karma Yoga, and Gnana Yoga among others. Ayyappa Vratham probably falls under the Bhakti Yoga but uses elements from other yogic pathways as well. Using devotion to bring out the divinity in human is the aim of Ayyappa Vratham. In under-taking the Vratham, we follow several rituals to signify the transformation of human nature to the divine nature.

Before looking at how Ayyappa Vratham helps us to transform ourselves and go towards Godhood, it will be useful to consider basic definition of Godliness. In practical terms, to have the union with God is to say, that we have godly qualities. What are the main characteristics of Godly qualities? God is love and love is God -some will say. God is peaceful - some will say as they seek God to have their own peace. Others will say God is truth and they seek God by seeking truth and or being truthful. And yet others will say that God is righteousness. In observing Ayyappa Vratham we are expected to show love to everyone as God is in everyone, be peaceful with ourselves and with others, be truthful, follow righteousness and of course non-violence. While opinions vary on how one sees God, everyone will agree that God is more powerful than man is. This is partly because God can control the nature both internal and external, better than man can. External nature is the elements like earth, wind, rain, sun etc. Internal nature of man is the qualities that man is not in full control yet strives, as a spiritual seeker, or a Sadhak to have control over the senses. In observing Ayyappa Vratham we try to have this internal control so we can go towards attaining godly qualities. In essence, Ayyappa Vratham is a "dress rehearsal" for preparing ourselves to be in union with God himself by surrendering his thoughts, words, and deeds and leading an austere life.  In other words, cleansing oneself of all impurities.

A Journey Towards God
Human birth is the most important and difficult to attain of all living creatures. To be born as human is in itself a blessing. The desire to reach God using this human form is another blessing bestowed on us by God. With both human form and the desire to go towards Him, we need a marga to reach God. In Vedic philosophy and in Sanadhana Dharma there are many ways to seek union with God. Ayyappa Vratham and the journey to Sabarimala is one,and perhaps, the most realistic way to reach him in this Kali yuga. In order to reach union with God, through any marga, we need to observe basic discipline in life. Ayyappa Vratham trains us to follow this discipline.

Guruswami: In Vedic samparadhya, to reach God we need the guidance of Guru. Guru is one who has been there and done that. Guru is one who can guide us, monitor our transformation and correct the mistakes we make on the way to attaining union with God . Thus, submission to Guru-swami is the key. Humility and humbleness is a hallmark of a Sathvic person. Ayyappa Vratham teaches us to be in submission to Guru and to fellow devotees. We consider Lord Ayyappa as Guru of all the Guruswamies.

41 Days of Mandala Vratham: Ayyappa Vratham observed for 41 days amounts to one mandalam period. This is the most essential first step to make the pilgrimage to Sabarimala. The idea is to follow the discipline continuously for a certain period so that it becomes habit. As they say, discipline on a daily basis forms the good habit; good habit forms  good character and good character determines our destiny. During this Vratham period, we attain basic purity of body, mind and spirit which is necessary for any devotional effort. Before starting the Vratham, we take permission from parents, seek the guidance of a Guruswami, and ask his permission and take permission from our Kuladeivam, family deity for blessings and protection.

Mudra or Thulasi Mala
Ayyappa Vratham is initiated with the invocation of God through adornment of the Thulasi mala. Lord Ayyappa is called Manikandan as the King Rajasekara Pandiyan found Him in the forest as a baby with manimala around his neck. Wearing Mudra mala symbolizes beginning of the Vratham. Mudramala reminds the devotee that he is God himself and to others it indicates that the devotee is in Vratham. The Mudra mala is removed when the Vratham is over after 41 days and after the devotee has the dharshan of Lord Ayyappa climbing 18 steps with the irumudikettu on his head.

Black Dhothi or Mundu: During the Vratham, the devotee lives like a Sanyasi and adorns black clothes as the color black denotes detachment from worldly things. There is no desire for dressing up.They do not cut hair, shave facial hair nor cut nails during the 41 days.  The effort is made towards keeping oneself clean. Hence, they take bath twice a day both in the morning and in the evening before the prayers during which the devotees chant 108 namas or sharanams.

A key essential of Ayyappa Vratham is the Sathvic lifestyleSimply put it is lifestyle of a sadhu. Sadhus keep their body, mind and soul clean, eat vegetarian food, and refrain from any bodily or mental pleasures and constantly think of God. Learning to lead a Sathvic life is a first step to recognize the devotional path. We do not hurt anyone by word, deed, or thought. Sathsang - Association with godly people helps in maintaining Sathvic lifestyle. Ayyappa congregations are a unique opportunity to associate with other Ayyappans who are also in Vratham and share the knowledge and experience.  Devotees see each other as Ayyappan himself and see God in every other creature. This association with other devotees is important for going through the daily tribulations in life as well. In sum, they  withdraw themselves from worldly affairs except for serving God and their fellow human beings and paticipate in spiritual activities like satsangh, prayers and bhajans. An essential part of Ayyappa Vratham is brahmacharyam. This is to not only keep our body and mind clean, but needed as basic requirement to get way from materialistic world. Brahmacharyam also helps us to conserve and concentrate all our physical energy and translate it to spiritual energy. We treat every woman as our mother during the Vratham.

Namasmaranam or saying "Swami Saranam" is important aspect of Ayyappa Vratham. "Swami Saranam" -Surrendering everything to God - is the moola manthram and moksha manthram of Ayyappa devotees. Some consider saying Swami Saranam is so powerful that it is equivalent to chanting Veda. Thinking about God all the time and chanting his name is a sure way towards God. It is also recommended as the easiest way to godliness. Yet in our daily life it is not often that we chant God’s name consciously. When devotees wear Mudra mala, they are often reminded if not all the time that they are to call his name all the time. They say "Swami Saranam" before starting and ending a conversation with anyone. This is another way to remember his name and at the same time to see God in others. In fact, they say Swami Saranam whenever their thought takes them away from the thought of God or when a distraction comes in the way or when they make a mistake during the Vratham. This is not only to ask forgiveness but also to remember God all the time. Therefore, Namasmaranam is the way of life when the devotees are in the Ayyappa Vratham. This, indeed,  needs to continue forever by all of us even when we are not in Vratham as Vratham is only a rehearsal period for how we should actually  lead our life as a devotee of Ayyappa. Namasangeerthanam is another way to chant God's name and remember God by singing his glory. Music has a tendency to to be etchedin our minds for days after we hear it. Hence, we should hear lots of bhajans, and songs that praise God  so that they will always keep ringing in our heads and are better than any other meaningless music. By joining a group that sings Bhajans, we cultivate a habit of regular praying.  Ayyappa Bhajans are regularly conducted in devotees homes and temples, which are the only places Ayyappa devotees, visit during the Vratham period.

Practice of reduction and eventual removal of kama, krotha, mada, maathsarya, lobha, moha is another key objective of Ayyappa Vratham. These are considered enemies of a spiritual man. Ayyappa Vratham is also an opportunity to practice moderation. Removal of desire, attachment to sensory world, yearning to harm or cause ruin to others, jealousy, and ego is the path to liberation from the cycle of birth and death. Ayyappa Vratham helps in avoiding these six obstacles.

lrumudikettu and journey to Sabarimala: At the end of the 41 days of Vratham period, we prepare irumudi to take it to the temple and dedicate it to Swami. The two bags represent the paavams and the punniyams each we have earned with our worldly activities and we surrender it to God and attain freedom from all Karmas good and bad.

As Lord Krishna declared in Bhagawat Gita and believed by ancient hindu sages, periodic fasts or vrathams purify the human mind and body. By adhering to an austere way of life observing tapas, observing daily prayers (in the morning and evening), participating in Sathsang and house pujas, doing community service through annadhanam, visiting temples regularly, imbibing in the spiritual literature, showing love and compassion to everyone and avoiding the six spiritual enemies as mentioned above, man trascends his earthly limitations and changes for the better.</string>
    <string name="select_file">Select File</string>
    <string name="title_activity_add_new_padi_puja">AddNewPadiPujaActivity</string>
    <string name="btn_cancel">Cancel</string>
    <string name="hint_old_password">Old Password</string>
    <string name="hint_new_password">New Password</string>
    <string name="hint_confirm_password">Confirm Password</string>
    <string name="btn_submit_small">Submit</string>
    <string name="title_activity_edit_profile">EditProfileActivity</string>
    <string name="title_activity_location">LocationActivity</string>
    <string name="title_activity_guru_swamy">GuruSwamyActivity</string>
    <string name="title_activity_musical_bands">MusicalBandsActivity</string>
    <string name="title_activity_mandap_vendors">MandapVendorsActivity</string>
    <string name="title_activity_ayyappa_hotels">AyyappaHotelsActivity</string>
    <string name="btn_save">save</string>
    <string name="hint_email">Email</string>
    <string name="hint_guru_swamy_name">Guru Swamy Name</string>
    <string name="hint_mandap_vendors_name">Mandap Vendors Name</string>
    <string name="hint_musical_bands_name">Musical band Name</string>
    <string name="hint_ayyappa_swamy_name">Ayyappa Swamy Name</string>
    <string name="hint_experience">Experience (in years)</string>
    <string name="hint_no_of_persons">No Of Persons</string>
    <string name="hint_ayyappa_swamy_hotels_name">Ayyappa Swami Hotel</string>
    <string name="hint_price">Price</string>
    <string name="title_activity_edit_guru_swamy">EditGuruSwamyActivity</string>
    <string name="title_activity_edit_mandap_vendors">EditMandapVendorsActivity</string>
    <string name="title_activity_edit_musical_bands">EditMusicalBandsActivity</string>
    <string name="title_activity_edit_ayyappa_hotels">EditAyyappaHotelsActivity</string>
    <string name="btn_verify_OTP_register"><![CDATA[Verify OTP & Register]]></string>
    <string name="hint_otp">Enter your  OTP</string>
    <string name="btn_verify">Verify</string>
    <string name="title_activity_before_edit_profile">BeforeEditProfileActivity</string>
    <string name="title_activity_my_subscriptions">MySubscriptionsActivity</string>
    <string name="title_activity_payment_gateway">PaymentGatewayActivity</string>
    <string name="title_activity_edit_regis_guru_swamy">EditRegisGuruSwamyActivity</string>
    <string name="title_activity_edit_regis_musical_band">EditRegisMusicalBandActivity</string>
    <string name="title_activity_edit_regis_mandap_vendors">EditRegisMandapVendorsActivity</string>
    <string name="title_activity_edit_regis_ayyappa_hotels">EditRegisAyyappaHotelsActivity</string>
    <string name="hint_song_name">Song Name</string>
    <string name="back"><![CDATA[<]]></string>
    <string name="rewind"><![CDATA[<<]]></string>
    <string name="forward"><![CDATA[>>]]></string>
    <string name="pause">||</string>
    <string name="title_activity_details_guru_swamy">DetailsGuruSwamyActivity</string>
    <string name="large_text">
        "Material is the metaphor.\n\n"

        "A material metaphor is the unifying theory of a rationalized space and a system of motion."
        "The material is grounded in tactile reality, inspired by the study of paper and ink, yet "
        "technologically advanced and open to imagination and magic.\n"
        "Surfaces and edges of the material provide visual cues that are grounded in reality. The "
        "use of familiar tactile attributes helps users quickly understand affordances. Yet the "
        "flexibility of the material creates new affordances that supercede those in the physical "
        "world, without breaking the rules of physics.\n"
        "The fundamentals of light, surface, and movement are key to conveying how objects move, "
        "interact, and exist in space and in relation to each other. Realistic lighting shows "
        "seams, divides space, and indicates moving parts.\n\n"

        "Bold, graphic, intentional.\n\n"

        "The foundational elements of print based design typography, grids, space, scale, color, "
        "and use of imagery guide visual treatments. These elements do far more than please the "
        "eye. They create hierarchy, meaning, and focus. Deliberate color choices, edge to edge "
        "imagery, large scale typography, and intentional white space create a bold and graphic "
        "interface that immerse the user in the experience.\n"
        "An emphasis on user actions makes core functionality immediately apparent and provides "
        "waypoints for the user.\n\n"

        "Motion provides meaning.\n\n"

        "Motion respects and reinforces the user as the prime mover. Primary user actions are "
        "inflection points that initiate motion, transforming the whole design.\n"
        "All action takes place in a single environment. Objects are presented to the user without "
        "breaking the continuity of experience even as they transform and reorganize.\n"
        "Motion is meaningful and appropriate, serving to focus attention and maintain continuity. "
        "Feedback is subtle yet clear. Transitions are efﬁcient yet coherent.\n\n"

        "3D world.\n\n"

        "The material environment is a 3D space, which means all objects have x, y, and z "
        "dimensions. The z-axis is perpendicularly aligned to the plane of the display, with the "
        "positive z-axis extending towards the viewer. Every sheet of material occupies a single "
        "position along the z-axis and has a standard 1dp thickness.\n"
        "On the web, the z-axis is used for layering and not for perspective. The 3D world is "
        "emulated by manipulating the y-axis.\n\n"

        "Light and shadow.\n\n"

        "Within the material environment, virtual lights illuminate the scene. Key lights create "
        "directional shadows, while ambient light creates soft shadows from all angles.\n"
        "Shadows in the material environment are cast by these two light sources. In Android "
        "development, shadows occur when light sources are blocked by sheets of material at "
        "various positions along the z-axis. On the web, shadows are depicted by manipulating the "
        "y-axis only. The following example shows the card with a height of 6dp.\n\n"

        "Resting elevation.\n\n"

        "All material objects, regardless of size, have a resting elevation, or default elevation "
        "that does not change. If an object changes elevation, it should return to its resting "
        "elevation as soon as possible.\n\n"

        "Component elevations.\n\n"

        "The resting elevation for a component type is consistent across apps (e.g., FAB elevation "
        "does not vary from 6dp in one app to 16dp in another app).\n"
        "Components may have different resting elevations across platforms, depending on the depth "
        "of the environment (e.g., TV has a greater depth than mobile or desktop).\n\n"

        "Responsive elevation and dynamic elevation offsets.\n\n"

        "Some component types have responsive elevation, meaning they change elevation in response "
        "to user input (e.g., normal, focused, and pressed) or system events. These elevation "
        "changes are consistently implemented using dynamic elevation offsets.\n"
        "Dynamic elevation offsets are the goal elevation that a component moves towards, relative "
        "to the component’s resting state. They ensure that elevation changes are consistent "
        "across actions and component types. For example, all components that lift on press have "
        "the same elevation change relative to their resting elevation.\n"
        "Once the input event is completed or cancelled, the component will return to its resting "
        "elevation.\n\n"

        "Avoiding elevation interference.\n\n"

        "Components with responsive elevations may encounter other components as they move between "
        "their resting elevations and dynamic elevation offsets. Because material cannot pass "
        "through other material, components avoid interfering with one another any number of ways, "
        "whether on a per component basis or using the entire app layout.\n"
        "On a component level, components can move or be removed before they cause interference. "
        "For example, a floating action button (FAB) can disappear or move off screen before a "
        "user picks up a card, or it can move if a snackbar appears.\n"
        "On the layout level, design your app layout to minimize opportunities for interference. "
        "For example, position the FAB to one side of stream of a cards so the FAB won’t interfere "
        "when a user tries to pick up one of cards.\n\n"
    </string>
    <string name="title_activity_details_musical_band">DetailsMusicalBandActivity</string>
    <string name="title_activity_details_mandap_vendors">DetailsMandapVendorsActivity</string>
    <string name="title_activity_details_ayyappa_hotels">DetailsAyyappaHotelsActivity</string>
    <string name="btn_subscribe">Subscribe</string>
    <string name="hint_subscription_name">Subscription Name</string>
    <string name="hint_validity">Validity</string>
    <string name="hint_amount">Amount</string>
    <string name="title_activity_details_padipuja">DetailsPadipujaActivity</string>
    <string name="title_activity_edit_swamy_profile">EditSwamyProfileActivity</string>
    <string name="title_activity_add_new_posts">AddNewPostsActivity</string>
    <string name="title_activity_friends">FriendsActivity</string>
</resources>
